urbanette.com 2019-07-28

# Privacy Policy & Contest Terms - URBANETTE: Lifestyle Magazine & Blog

In summary: A) We keep your information safe, and B) you can enter contests if you live in the USA.

## Privacy Policy

What information do we gather about you?

The information we gather falls into two categories:

  1. personal information you voluntarily supply when you subscribe, order, complete a survey, or provide your email address and
  2. tracking information collected as you navigate through our site.

### Paid Products

While our website is free, we do sell products such as subscriptions and back issues. To enable the purchase of these and other products, we do not store your billing  information. Billing information stays on the payment processor: Amazon.com or Google.com, and only your name, email and address is shared with us.

### Reader Surveys, Reader Panels and Market Research

Urbanette Magazine may collect personal information from readers in connection with voluntary surveys. Data may be collected on our website, on the phone or via email. Readers are primarily contacted via email, which link to online surveys, but may occasionally be contacted by mail. All survey data is reported and/or used in aggregate form only, and no personally identifiable information is released.

### Aggregate Information Collected Through Technology

  * Cookies and Other Technologies

As is standard practice on many websites, Urbanette Magazine uses “cookies” and other technologies to recognize you to help us understand which parts of our website are the most popular, where our visitors are going and how much time they spend there. We use Google Analytics to do some of this collection. We reserve the right to change the vendors who provide us with usage data.

  * IP Addresses

We use the IP address log in an aggregate fashion to track access to our site. Log data is  used in aggregate to analyze usage of our website.

## What do we do with the information we gather about you?

### Statistical Analysis

Urbanette Magazine may perform statistical, demographic and marketing analyses of subscribers, and their subscribing and purchasing patterns, for marketing and customer service purposes

### Products and Services from Urbanette Magazine

From time to time, we may provide customers with information and offers about other products offered by Urbanette Magazine, including subscriptions, back issues and renewals. This information will only be shared internally. If you do not wish to receive such information and offers, you may opt-out.

### Email Newsletters

If you choose to receive them, Urbanette Magazine will periodically send you email newsletters or promotional email about services offered by Urbanette Magazine and occasionally events that Urbanette Magazine participates in. If you no longer wish to receive a specific newsletter, follow the “unsubscribe” instructions located near the bottom of each newsletter. To manage your Urbanette Magazine email preferences, use the manage/change link on the email we sent you.

Urbanette Magazine complies fully with the federal CAN-SPAM Act of 2003. We will not share, sell, rent, swap or authorize any third party to use your email address. If you feel you have received an email from us in error, please contact editor [at] urbanette.com.

### Account and Service-Related Email

Urbanette Magazine reserves the right to send you email relating to your account status. This includes order confirmations, renewal/expiration notices, notices of account problems, other transactional emails and notifications about major changes to our website and/or to our Privacy Policy. If you have registered for online discussions or other services, you may receive email specific to your participation in those activities.

### Reader Comments

This site uses Akismet to reduce spam. [Learn how your comment data is processed](https://akismet.com/privacy/).

### Survey Email

We may send you an email inviting you to participate in user surveys. User surveys greatly help us to improve our Web site and magazine and any information we obtain in such surveys will not be shared with third parties.

### Emails From You

If you send us email, you should be aware that information disclosed in email may not be secure or encrypted and thus may be available to others. We suggest that you exercise caution when deciding to disclose any personal or confidential information via email. We will use your email address to respond directly to your questions or comments.

### Email This Article Feature

Urbanette Magazine readers may use this feature to send links to articles to others through email. The email address(es) that you supply to this service will only be used to send the requested article.

## With whom do we share the information we gathered?

Urbanette Magazine will not sell, rent, swap or authorize any third party to use your email address without your permission.

If you are a print subscriber to Urbanette Magazine magazine and subscribed either by mail, phone or online, we may exchange or rent your name and mailing address (but not your email address) with other like-minded organizations through direct mail. If you prefer that we do not share this information, you may opt-out, by emailing customer service.

### Service Providers

We contract with other companies to provide services on our behalf, including credit-card and billing processing, shipping, and website analytics. We provide these companies only with the information they need to perform their services. These service providers are restricted from using this data in any way other than to provide services for Urbanette Magazine, and they may not share or resell this data.

## How to opt-out from receiving promotional offers

### Email Promotions

If, at any time, you prefer not to receive email marketing information from us, simply follow the unsubscribe options at the bottom of each email. To manage your Urbanette Magazine email preferences, please go to the manage/change link in the email newsletter.

If you experience difficulty with the unsubscribe process, feel free to contact us at editor [at] urbanette.com and provide your email address along with the name of the newsletter from which you would like to unsubscribe.

### Print Promotions

If you prefer that we do not share your address, you may opt-out, either by logging in to your account and choosing that option, or by emailing customer service. Email us at editor [at] urbanette.com, put “don’t share my name” in the subject and include in the body your subscriber number and name. If you don’t know your subscriber number (found on the address label of the magazine), you will need to include your address as well, so we can correctly identify you.

Next page: >Official Rules for Online Contests
